filezilla-project.org 2019-11-13

# FileZilla - Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. This page describes the privacy policy applicable to the services using the filezilla-project.org domain ( _the website_ ) as well as the FileZilla software products ( _the software_ ).

For the processing of personal data we, as data controller, adhere to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) of the European Union. To that effect, the users of our website and our software are the data subjects.

### Data processing on our Website

When visiting our website, each page access is temporarily logged in order to combat abuse and to ensure the health of _the website_. This data includes the page accessed, the time of access, the IP address and the browser's user agent. This data is not shared with any third party and is automatically deleted after no more than 10 days. Data processing is in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR.

For the purpose of displaying advertisement, the assumed country of origin of page visitors may be submitted to advertisers.

For statistical purposes, anonymized data may be collected in aggregate form from which no information about individual users can be infered. This data may be shared with third parties.

Some services on _the website_ allow you to register an account, requiring you to enter your e-mail address in addition to a username of your choice upon account creation. All actions made using an account are logged, including account name, IP-address and content. Your account profile as well as all texts and images posted using your account are publicly visible. Data retention is potentially unlimited unless removal is requested by you or required by law. We do not share non-public data with third parties. Registering an account and the subsequent data processing requires consent in accordance to Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR.

Some services on _the website_ may use cookies for session handling. If you do not want to use cookies you can disable them in your webbrowser settings. These cookies are not being shared with third parties. Data processing is in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR to ensure the best possible and user-friendly functionality of the services.

### Data processing in our Software

_The software_ may periodically and automatically contact _the website_ to query the latest version of _the software_. For technical reasons, _the software_ 's version, your operating system name and the processor architecture of your system are being submitted, in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR. This data is not being shared with any third party. For statistical purposes, anonymized data may be collected in aggregate form from which no information about individual users can be infered.

We may use third-party advertising companies in offer-enabled installers to serve ads when you install our software. The advertisers' privacy policies can be reviewed at the start of the installer before any ads are served.

We do not otherwise record any personally identifiable information or information about the way you use _the software_ without your prior consent.

### Your rights

You have the right to access to, rectification of, erasure of, restriction of processing of, and portability of your personal data pursuant to Articles 15, 16, 17, 18, 20 of the GDPR respectively.

You have the right to withdraw consent to proccesing pursuant Art. 7 (3) GDPR.

You have the right to object to processing pursuant Art. 21 GDPR.

Please contact [privacy@filezilla-project.org](mailto:privacy@filezilla-project.org) if you wish to exercise any of these rights and we will respond to your request without undue delay.

We do not use automatic decision-making subject to Art. 22 GDPR.

You further have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority pursuant to Art. 77 GDPR.

### Contact information

The controller responsible for this privacy policy and the data processing is Tim Kosse, Lukasstr. 10, 50823 Cologne, Germany.

Please direct all questions regarding this policy to [privacy@filezilla-project.org](mailto:privacy@filezilla-project.org).

This policy has been last updated on 2019-09-09.
